

Senior Software Engineer Berlin, Germany

+49 176 6535 5475

me@marceloboeira.com http://marceloboeira.com

SUMMARY

Senior Backend Engineer with 5+ years of experience working on large-scale web applications for huge companies such as Globo.com, 3M, and Walmart.

Passionate about clean code, quality, testing, performance, and open source. Currently, looking for a **challenging position** with promising future.

EDUCATION

Electronics Engineering — Unisinos — 2012-2017*
Electrical and Electronics Development — SENAI — 2010-2012

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer at Crealytics

Berlin, Germany — 08/2016 to 12/2016

Backend Developer creating customer solutions and internal tools with Ruby.

Software Engineer at Globo.com

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil — 04/2015 to 07/2016

As a backend engineer in the videos team, I have handled modeling, background processing, microservices, scalability and availability issues on daily basis. All that in order to provide a trustable and scalable publishing entry point for videos at Globo.com.

Accomplishments:

- Distributed application architecture (around 100 instances running all over the country)
- Massive application demand (Transcoding over 500GB of video per day)
- Digital video fingerprinting (Copyright Content ID for Youtube, Facebook ...)

Software Developer at Prime Systems

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil — 01/2014 to 03/2015

I have worked as a full-stack developer, dealing with backend and front-end problems and also deploy issues. With a great team support, I have worked on the development and maintenance of five very active web applications, with mobile API service and a huge amount of active users.

Accomplishments

- Learned more about TDD, RoR, Refactoring and Design Patterns
- Participated in the development of an automated deploy structure
- Worked with a huge application structure, over 50 thousand active users
- Worked full-time Home-office based

Software Developer at Núcleo Sistemas

Caxias do Sul, RS, Brazil — 01/2011 to 02/2013

I have led a web development team on the migration of an old desktop ERP into a modern SaaS cloud-based web application, with PHP, OOP, MVC, Zend Framework, Node JS for socket/realtime features.

Accomplishments

- Led a team
- Implemented a powerful web application since the scratch